Fergadiotis Manos

NLP Researcher / Data Scientist

Email: manosfer@hotmail.com

Mobile Phone: +30 6945706803

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/manos-fergadiotis

Data scientist with an interest in artificial intelligence and machine learning. Academic and industrial research experience in deep learning methods used in natural language processing tasks. Team member with advanced analytical thinking and creative problem-solving skills.

Research assistant at the Natural Language Processing Group of Athens University of Economics and Business

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Research Engineer NCSR Demokritos

2019 - Present

Doing research on various NLP areas in the legal and financial domain: Information Retrieval, Text Classification, Named Entity Recognition

> Design and implementation of core architecture for Deep Learning models

Data Scientist Cognitiv+ 2018 – 2019

- > Applying Deep Learning to legal text to resolve various NLP tasks: Element Extraction, Text Classification
- > Design and implementation of core architecture for Deep Learning models

Web Development and Promotion Freelancer

2015 - 2017

Website and E-Shop Development, Search Engine Optimization, Google AdWords, Facebook Ads

EDUCATION

B.Sc. Computer Science Grade: 7.7 / 10

Department of Informatics, Athens University of Economics and Business

M.Sc. Data Science Grade: 9.2 / 10

Departments of Informatics and Statistics, Athens University of Economics and Business

RESEARCH INTERESTS

- Machine Learning especially deep learning methods used on natural language processing tasks
- ➤ Legal Text Analytics
- > Information extraction and data mining
- > Text classification
- Sentiment analysis

PUBLICATIONS

FiNER: Financial Numeric Entity Recognition for XBRL Tagging

Lefteris Loukas, Manos Fergadiotis, Ilias Chalkidis, Eirini Spyropoulou, Prodromos Malakasiotis, Ion Androutsopoulos and George Paliouras

In the Proceedings of the 60th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL 2022), Dublin, Republic of Ireland, May 22–27, 2022.

> MultiEURLEX - A multi-lingual and multi-label legal document classification dataset for zero-shot cross-lingual transfer

Ilias Chalkidis, Manos Fergadiotis, and Ion Androutsopoulos In the Proceedings of the Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP 2021), Punta Cana, Dominican Republic, November 7–11, 2021.

Paragraph-level Rationale Extraction through Regularization: A case study on European Court of Human Rights Cases

Ilias Chalkidis, Manos Fergadiotis, Dimitrios Tsarapatsanis, Nikolaos Aletras, Ion Androutsopoulos and Prodromos Malakasiotis

In the Proceedings of the Annual Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (NAACL 2021), (Held online due to COVID-19), June 6–11, 2021.

> Neural Contract Element Extraction Revisited: Letters from Sesame Street

Ilias Chalkidis, Manos Fergadiotis, Prodromos Malakasiotis and Ion Androutsopoulos Pre-print (Update of the article "Neural Contract Element Extraction Revisited"), February 23, 2021.

Regulatory Compliance through Doc2Doc Information Retrieval: A case study in EU/UK legislation where text similarity has limitations

Ilias Chalkidis, Manos Fergadiotis, Nikolaos Manginas and Prodromos Malakasiotis In the Proceedings of the 16th Conference of the European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (EACL 2021), (Held online due to COVID-19), April 21–23, 2021.

Using Textual Analysis to Identify Merger Participants: Evidence from the U.S. Banking Industry Apostolos Katsafados, Ion Androutsopoulos, Ilias Chalkidis, Manos Fergadiotis, George Leledakis and Emmanouil Pyrgiotakis

In Finance Research Letters, January 26, 2021.

An Empirical Study on Large-Scale Multi-Label Text Classification including Few and Zero-Shot Labels

Ilias Chalkidis, Manos Fergadiotis, Sotiris Kotitsas, Prodromos Malakasiotis, Nikolaos Aletras and Ion Androutsopoulos

In the Proceedings of the Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP 2020), (Held online due to COVID-19), November 16–20, 2020.

> LEGAL-BERT: "The Muppets straight out of Law School"

Ilias Chalkidis, Manos Fergadiotis, Prodromos Malakasiotis, Nikolaos Aletras and Ion Androutsopoulos In Findings of Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP 2020), November 16–20, 2020.

> Neural Contract Element Extraction Revisited

Ilias Chalkidis, Manos Fergadiotis, Prodromos Malakasiotis and Ion Androutsopoulos In the Proceedings of the Document Intelligence Workshop - co-located with NeurIPS 2019, Vancouver, Canada, December 8-14, 2019.

Large-Scale Multi-Label Text Classification on EU Legislation

Ilias Chalkidis, Manos Fergadiotis, Prodromos Malakasiotis and Ion Androutsopoulos In the Proceedings of the 57th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL 2019) (Short Papers), Florence, Italy, July 28 - August 2, 2019.

> Extreme Multi-Label Legal Text Classification: A case study in EU Legislation

Ilias Chalkidis, Manos Fergadiotis, Prodromos Malakasiotis, Nikolaos Aletras and Ion Androutsopoulos In the Proceedings of the Workshop on Natural Legal Language Processing - co-located with NAACL-HLT 2019, Minneapolis, USA, June 2-7, 2019.

The Predictions of Bank Merger Targets and Acquirers with Textual Analysis

George Leledakis, Apostolos Katsafados, Ion Androutsopoulos, Ilias Chalkidis, Emmanouel Fergadiotis In the Proceedings of the 9th National Conference of the Financial Engineering and Banking Society (FEBS 2018), Athens, Greece, 2018.

The Effect of Textual Information on IPO Underpricing

Ion Androutsopoulos, Ilias Chalkidis, Emmanouel Fergadiotis, Apostolos Katsafados, George Leledakis and Alexandra Ntetsika

In the Proceedings of the 8th National Conference of the Financial Engineering and Banking Society (FEBS 2017), Athens, Greece, December 18-19, 2017. 2017.

REVIEWING

- > ACL Rolling Review, 2022
- > ACL Rolling Review, 2021
- Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP), 2021
- > 2nd Workshop on Natural Legal Language Processing (NLLP), Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining (KDD 2020), 2020
- > 1st Workshop on Natural Legal Language Processing (NLLP), Annual Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (NAACL-HL), 2019

SKILLS AND ABILITIES

➤ **Deep Learning Frameworks** Keras • TensorFlow • PyTorch

▶ Programming Languages
Python • Java • C • C++ • MatLab • SQL

Code Repositories
GitHub, GitLab, Bitbucket

➤ Web Technologies
PHP • HTML • JavaScript • jQuery • CSS • MySQL

Virtualization & OS
VMware • VirtualBox • Linux • Windows

Cloud Platforms Google Cloud Platform (GCP)

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Greek Native

English Proficient (CEFR: C2)